Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on The Socialist International PE.046
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on The Socialist International
1950-1986
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
PE.046
2 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on The Socialist International is an artificial collection, collected and assembled by the Tamiment Library over the course of several decades. The Socialist International is the worldwide organization of social democratic, socialist, and labour parties. The collection consists of printed matter ranging in date from 1950-1986. Contained within the files are press releases, bulletins, publications, and a selection of circulars put out by the Socialist International, both general circulars as well as ones published for bureau members. There is also material from the Congresses both in Albufeira, Portugal (1983) and Madrid, Spain (1980). A portion of the collection comes from various sections of the Socialist International, including the Socialist International Women and its predecessor, the International Council of Social Democratic Women, and the International Council of Socialist Youth.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Socialist International is the worldwide organization of social democratic, socialist, and labour parties. Its origins go back to the early international organizations of the labour movement, and has existed in its present form since 1951, when it was re-established at the Frankfurt Congress. Since then it has been increasingly active and grown considerably in membership, more than doubling the number of its members in recent years. Labour, social democratic, and socialist parties are now a major political force in democracies around the world, with numerous member parties of the Socialist International leading governments or representing the main opposition force.
Custodial History
The provenance of the materials is varied. Items were obtained through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, arrangements with labor unions and other organizations, exchanges with other libraries, and through ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff. A majority of this collection was separated from the Democratic Socialists of America Collection (TAM 105).
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Democratic Socialists of America Collection (TAM 105)
Arrangement
Material is arranged alphabetically.
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on The Socialist International contains public printed material published by the Socialist International and its women's section, the Socialist International Women, as well as its youth section, the International Union of Socialist Youth. The materials in the collection range in date from 1950-1986. Contained within are press releases, bulletins, publications, and a selection of circulars. The circulars are labeled as either "general" or for "bureau members." There is one poster from the Socialist International Women pertaining to their 1979 "International Year of the Child."
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library. There is no accession record associated with this collection.
Pamphlets.; Press releases.; Circular letters.; Socialist International (1951- ); International Union of Socialist Youth; Socialist International Women (Organization)
- Circulars, 1951-1952 (Box 1)
- Circulars I, 1977 (Box 1)
- Circulars II, 1977 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members I, 1977 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members II, 1977 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members III, 1977 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members I, 1978 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members II, 1978 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members I, 1979 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members II, 1979 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members I, 1980 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members II, 1980 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members III, 1980 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members I, 1981 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members II, 1981 (Box 1)
- Circulars: Bureau Members, 1982-1984 (Box 1)
- Circulars: General I, 1978 (Box 1)
- Circulars: General II, 1978 (Box 1)
- Circulars: General, 1979 (Box 1)
- Circulars: General I, 1980 (Box 1)
- Circulars: General II, 1980 (Box 1)
- Circulars: General III, 1980 (Box 1)
- Circulars: General, 1981 (Box 1)
- Circulars: General, 1982 (Box 1)
- Circulars: General, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
- Congress (Albufeira, Portugal), 1983 (Box 1)
- Congress (Madrid, Spain) I, 1980 (Box 1)
- Congress (Madrid, Spain) II, 1980 (Box 1)
- Congress (Madrid, Spain) III, 1980 (Box 1)
- Congress (Madrid, Spain) IV, 1980 (Box 2)
- Declaration: "Aims and Tasks of Democratic Socialism", 1951 (Box 2)
- General, 1956-1964 (Box 2)
- History of, undated (Box 2)
- International Council of Social Democratic Women: Bulletin, 1974-1978 (Box 2)
- International Council of Social Democratic Women: Circulars, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
- International Falcon Movement: Socialist Educational International, 1981 (Box 2)
- International Federation of the Socialist and Democratic Press, 1982 (Box 2)
- International Union of Socialist Youth: Bulletin, 1979-1981 (Box 2)
- International Union of Socialist Youth: Pamphlets and Publications, undated (Box 2)
- Message to Women of All Countries, undated (Box 2)
- Official Address List, undated (Box 2)
- Pamphlets and Publications, 1962-1969 (Box 2)
- Pamphlets and Publications, 1970-1976 (Box 2)
- Pamphlets and Publications, undated (Box 2)
- Press Releases, 1978 (Box 2)
- Press Releases, 1979 (Box 2)
- Press Releases, 1980 (Box 2)
- Press Releases, 1981 (Box 2)
- Press Releases, 1982 (Box 2)
- Press Releases, 1983 (Box 2)
- Press Releases, 1984 (Box 2)
- Press Releases, 1986 (Box 2)
- SI News, 1973-1977 (Box 2)
- Socialist Affairs, 1973-1975 (Box 2)
- Socialist Affairs, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
- Socialist Affairs, 1978-1983 (Box 2)
- Socialist Group European Parliament, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women, 1983, undated (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women: Bulletin, 1979-1981 (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women: Bureau Meeting: Minutes, 1983 (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women: Circulars, 1979 (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women: Circulars I, 1980 (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women: Circulars II, 1980 (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women: Circulars, 1981 (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women: Circulars, 1982-1985 (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women: Circulars, 1986 (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women: Pamphlets, 1982-1985 (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women: Poster "International Year of the Child", 1979 (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women: Proceeding of the Seminar on Socialism and Feminism I, 1980 (Box 2)
- Socialist International Women: Proceeding of the Seminar on Socialism and Feminism II, 1980 (Box 2)
- Speech: "Socialism and Peace", 1950 (Box 2)
- Union des Partis Socialistes de la Communaute' Europeene, 1980 (Box 2)